Guide to the Pacific Improvement Company Records, 1869-1931 (inclusive), 1883-1927 (bulk) JL001
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Series 4. Business Record Books, Many of the volumes in this series were badly burned and have been wrapped in brown paper. Most of these are in fair condition, but several are extremely fragile and were left in their wrapping. Those items with no dates are, for the most part, those in less than f
  - CARBON HILL COAL COMPANY (WASHINGTON STATE)
    - Mining Reports, May-Dec 1918 (Box 295b, Folder 15)
    - Mining Reports, March-June 1919
    - Tonnage Report, 1915 (Box 295c, Folder 16)
    - Store Inventory, Dec 31, 1921 and 1922 (Box 295c, Folder 17)
    - Balance Sheets, 1922-1923 (Box 295c, Folder 18)
    - Carbon Hill Coal Co. option, 1918 (Box 295c, Folder 19)
    - Cost Reports, (no folders), 1914-1916
    - Journal, 1906-1910 (Volume 296)
    - Ledger, 1906-1910 (Volume 297)
    - Ledger Register, April 1922-Jan 1923 (Volume 298)
    - Ledger Register, Feb 1923-Nov 1923 (Volume 299)
    - Ledger Register, Dec 1923-Dec 1926 (Volume 300)
    - Individual Ledger, 1907-1908 (Volume 301)
    - Individual Ledger, 1911-1924 (Volume 302)
    - Company Ledgers, 1911-1924 (Volume 303)
    - Company Ledgers, 1918-1922 (Volume 304)
    - Company Ledgers, 1918-1924 (Volume 305)
    - Voucher Record, 1913-1918 (Volume 306)
    - Voucher Record, 1919-1924 (Volume 307)
    - Voucher Record, 1918-1924 (Volume 308)
    - Cash Receipts Book, 1918-1924 (Volume 309)
    - Vouchers, (12161-12228), 1922 (Volume 310)
    - Vouchers, (1000-1175) and (2000-2213), 1923 (Volume 311)
    - Vouchers, (3000-4050), 1923 (Volume 312)
    - Vouchers, (4051-5150), 1923 (Volume 313)
    - Vouchers, (5151-6211), 1923 (Volume 314)
    - Vouchers, (7000-8120), 1923 (Volume 315)
    - Vouchers, (8121-10050), 1923 (Volume 316)
    - Vouchers, (10051-11160), 1923 (Volume 317)
    - Vouchers, (11161-12247), 1923 (Volume 318)
    - Vouchers, (1000-1100), 1924
    - Vouchers, (1101-2200), 1924 (Volume 319)
    - Vouchers, (2201-3266), 1924 (Volume 320)
    - Vouchers, (4000-5050), 1924 (Volume 321)
    - Vouchers, (5051-6060), 1924 (Volume 322)
    - Vouchers, (6061-7100), 1924 (Volume 323)
    - Vouchers, (7101-8075), 1924 (Volume 324)
    - Journal Vouchers (Volume 325)
      - Jan-March 1923
      - April-June 1923
    - Journal Vouchers (Volume 326)
      - July-Sept 1923
      - Oct-Dec 1923
    - Store Purchases, 1923-1924 (Volume 327)
    - Paycheck Register and check register, 1919-1924 (Volume 328)
    - Production and Shipping Report, 1917-1923 (Volume 329)
  - CASTLE CRAGS FARM AND COTTAGES (CALIFORNIA)
    - Daybook, 1913 (Volume 330)
    - Journal, 1913 (Volume 331)
    - Ledger, 1913 (Volume 332)
    - Petty Cash Book, 1912 (Volume 332a)
    - Checkbook, 1912 (Volume 333)
    - Checkbook, 1913 (Volume 334)
  - HOTEL DEL MONTE, PACIFIC GROVE, SANTA BARBARA RANCH
    - Guest Record, (Hotel Del Monte), 1895-1906 (Volume 335)
    - Guest Record, (Pacific Grove Hotel), 1904-1915 (Volume 336)
    - Ledger, (Pacific Grove Restaurant), 1884-1885 (Volume 337)
    - Scrapbook, (Del Monte and Pacific Grove), [1908?] (Volume 338)
    - Accounts, (Pacific Grove and Miscellaneous), 1914 (Volume 339)
    - Accounts Receivable, (Pacific Grove and Santa Barbara), 1915-1917 (Volume 340)
    - Journal, (Santa Barbara Ranch), 1910-1915 (Volume 341)
    - Ledger, (Santa Barbara Ranch), 1913-1914 (Volume 342)
    - Petty Ledger, (Santa Barbara Ranch), 1912-1913 (Volume 343)
  - SONOMA VALLEY IMPROVEMENT COMPANY (CALIFORNIA)
    - By laws and Articles of Incorporation, 1888 (Volume 344)
    - Stock Certificates (Volume 345)
    - Stock Journal, 1888 (Volume 346)
    - Abstract of Titles, Petaluma Rancho, 1888-1890 (Volume 347)
    - Journal, 1901-1913 (Volume 348)
    - Journal, (includes El Verano entries), 1896-1899 (Volume 349)
    - Journal, (includes El Verano entries), 1896-1901 (Volume 350)
    - Cash Book, (includes El Verano entries), 1896-1901. (Volume 351)
    - Ledger, 1890-1899 (Volume 352)
    - Ledger, 1901-1913 (Volume 353)
    - Ledger, (includes El Verano entries), 1896-1899 (Volume 354)
    - Cash Book, 1887-1899 (Volume 355)
    - Cash Book, 1901-1913 (Volume 356)
    - Cash and Stock Book, 1893-1905 (Volume 357)
    - Inventory, 1900-1912 (Volume 358)
  - EL VERANO VILLA ASSOCIATION (CALIFORNIA)
    - By laws and Articles of Association, 1914 (Volume 359)
    - Miscellaneous papers, including deeds, resolutions, 1908-1919
    - Minutes, 1914-1920
    - Stock Certificates, 1891-1915
    - Stock Journal and Ledger, 1914 (Volume 359)
    - Journal, 1914-1920
    - Ledger, 1914-1920
  - EL VERANO IMPROVEMENT ASSOCIATION (CALIF.)
    - Articles of Association, 1914 (Volume 360)
    - Minutes, 1914-1920
    - Stock Certificates, 1891-1896
    - Stock Journal and Ledger, 1914-1919
    - Journal, 1914-1920
    - Ledger, 1914-1920
    - Journal, (El Verano Farm), 1914-1920
    - Ledger, (El Verano Farm), 1914-1915
  - GEARY STREET PARK AND OCEAN RAILWAY CO.
    - Original By laws (Volume 361)
    - By laws, 1887 (Volume 362)
    - Index to Minutes (Volume 363)
    - Minutes, 1878-1892 (Volume 364)
    - Minutes, 1893-1906 (Volume 365)
    - Minutes, 1913-1917 (Volume 366)
    - Stock Certificates (Volume 367)
    - Stock Certificates, 1906 (Volume 368)
    - Stock Journal, 1882-1917 (Volume 369)
    - Stock Ledger (Volume 370)
    - Unissued bonds (Volume 371)
    - Issued bonds (Volume 372)
    - Dividends (Volume 373)
    - Dividends, 1883-1884 (Volume 373a)
    - Dividends, 1885-1886 (Volume 374)
    - Dividend Check Book (Volume 374a)
    - Journal, 1906-1924 (Volume 375)
    - Cactus Ledger, 1880-1917 (Volume 376)
    - Ledger, 1906-1924 (Volume 377)
    - Cash Book, 1879-1887 (Volume 378)
    - Cash Book, 1880-1882 (Volume 379)
    - Cash Book, 1882-1883 (Volume 380)
    - Cash Book, 1885-1887 (Volume 381)
    - Cash Book, 1906-1908 (Volume 382)
    - Cash Book, 1908-1912 (Volume 383)
    - Cash Book, 1912-1918 (Volume 384)
    - Distribution Journal, 1887-1906 (Volume 385)
    - Receipts and Rentals, 1905-1912 (Volume 386)
    - Register of Vouchers, 1894-1906 (Volume 387)
    - Register of Vouchers, 1907-1912 (Volume 388)
  - GUATEMALA CENTRAL RAILROAD COMPANY
    - By laws, 1885 (Volume 389)
    - Minutes, 1878-1885 (Volume 390)
    - Minutes, 1885-1906 (Volume 391)
    - Stock Certificates (2 books) (Volume 392)
    - Stock Ledger (Volume 393)
    - Journal (Volume 394)
    - Ledger (Volume 395)
    - Statements and Balance Sheets, 1906-1912 (Volume 396)
  - IONE COAL AND IRON COMPANY (CALIFORNIA)
    - By laws, 1906 (Volume 397)
    - Minutes, 1906-1921 (Volume 398)
    - Stock Journal, 1906-1919 (Volume 399)
    - Stock Ledger, 1898-1921 (Volume 400)
    - Stock Certificates, 1906-1912 (Volume 401)
    - Stock Certificates, 1916-1919 (Volume 402)
    - Stock Certificates, 1918-1921 (Volume 403)
    - Journal, 1906-1907 (Volume 404)
    - Journal, 1899-1913 (Volume 405)
    - Journal, 1914-1916 (Volume 406)
    - Ledger, 1899-1913 (Volume 407)
    - Ledger, 1907-1913 (Volume 408)
    - Ledger, 1914-19169 (Volume 409)
    - General Ledger, 1916-1917 (Volume 410)
    - Cash Book, Jan-July 1906 (Volume 411)
    - Cash Book, July-Nov 1906 (Volume 412)
    - Cash Book, 1909-1916 (Volume 413)
    - Trial Balance, 1909-1914 (Volume 414)
    - Accounts Payable, 1914-1917 (Volume 415)
    - Accounts Receivable, 1914-1917 (Volume 416)
    - General Records, 1916-1922 (Volume 416a)
    - Voucher Record, 1917-1921 (Volume 417)
    - Time Book, 1907-1909 (Volume 418)
  - LAGUNA BLANCA WATER COMPANY
    - By laws (Volume 419)
    - Minutes (Volume 420)
    - Stock Journal and Ledger (Volume 421)
  - MONTEREY COUNTY WATER WORKS
    - By laws, 1907 (Volume 422)
    - Minutes, 1907-1908 (Volume 423)
    - Stock Certificates (Volume 424)
    - Stock Journal, 1905-1908 (Volume 425)
    - Stock Ledger, 1905-1908 (Volume 426)
    - Journal, 1906-1907 (Volume 427)
    - Ledger, 1906-1907 (Volume 428)
  - OAKLAND WATER FRONT COMPANY
    - By laws, 1869 (Volume 429)
    - Index to Minutes (Volume 430)
    - Minutes, 1868-1903 (Volume 431)
    - Minutes, 1906-1915 (Volume 432)
    - Stock Certificates, 1898-1920 (Volume 433)
    - Addenda
      - Stock Cert. (Volume 433a)
      - Stock journal (Volume 434a)
      - Stock ledger (Volume 435a)
    - Stock Journal, 1868-1913 (Volume 434)
    - Stock Ledger, 1868-1917 (Volume 435)
    - Journal, 1907-1918 (Volume 436)
    - General Expense Book, 1919-1920 (Volume 437)
    - Cash Book, 1906-1918 (Volume 438)
    - Trial Balance, (includes entries of Guatemala Central RR Co. and Union Fuel Company), 1911-1914 (Volume 439)
    - Record of Leases and Contracts, 1900-1910 (Volume 440)
  - PACIFIC LUMBER TRANSPORTATION COMPANY
    - Journal, 1908-1909 (Volume 441)
    - Journal, 1910-1912 (Volume 442)
    - Ledger, 1909-1912 (Volume 443)
    - Ledger, 1913-1916 (Volume 444)
    - Cash Book, 1909-1912 (Volume 445)
  - ROCKY MOUNTAIN COAL AND IRON COMPANY (WYOMING)
    - By laws, 1870 (Volume 446)
    - By laws, no date (Volume 447)
    - By laws, (Rocky Mountain Mercantile Co.), no date (Volume 447a)
    - Minutes, no date (Volume 447b)
    - Minutes, 1907-1920 (Volume 447c)
    - Minutes, (Rocky Mountain Mercantile Co.), 1907-1920 (Volume 447)
    - Stock Journal, 1906-1919 (Volume 448)
    - Stock Journal, 1907-1920 (Volume 449)
    - Stock Journal, no date (Volume 450)
    - Stock Ledger, 1907-1920 (Volume 451)
    - Stock Ledger, no date (Volume 452)
    - Stock Certificates, 1881-1820 (Volume 453)
    - Stock Certificates, no date (Volume 454)
    - Stock Certificates, (Rocky Mountain Mercantile Co.), 1907-1920 (Volume 455)
    - Journal, 1907-1913 (Volume 456)
    - Journal, 1914-1920 (Volume 457)
    - Journal, (Rocky Mountain Mercantile Co.), 1907-1920 (Volume 458)
    - Cactus Ledger, 1878-1919 (Volume 459)
    - Ledger, 1907-1909 (Volume 460)
    - Ledger, 1909-1913 (Volume 461)
    - Ledger, 1914-1919 (Volume 462)
    - Ledger, (Rocky Mountain Mercantile Co.), 1907-1920 (Volume 463)
    - Cash Book, 1907-1913 (Volume 464)
    - Cash Book, (Rocky Mountain Mercantile Co.), 1907-1908 (Volume 465)
    - Trial Balance, 1906-1914 (Volume 466)
  - SACRAMENTO PUBLISHING COMPANY
    - Minutes (Volume 467)
  - SS SAN MATEO
    - Ship's Log, 1904-1905 (Volume 468)
    - Ship's Diary, 1917-1918 (Volume 469)
  - SOUTHERN DEVELOPMENT COMPANY
    - By laws (Volume 470)
    - Index to Minutes (Volume 471)
    - Minutes, 1881-1889
    - Minutes, 1889-1907
    - Stockholders, 1881-1901 (Volume 472)
    - Stock Journal (Volume 473)
    - Stock Certificates, 1881-1894 (Volume 473a)
    - Journal, 1884-1890 (Volume 474)
    - Journal, 1891 (Volume 475)
    - Ledger, 1884-1890 (Volume 476)
    - Ledger, 1891 (Volume 477)
    - Index to General Ledger A (No. 477) (Volume 478)
    - Cash Book, 1885-1886 (Volume 479)
    - Cash Book, 1886-1890 (Volume 480)
    - Cash Book, 1890 (Volume 481)
    - Cash Book, 1891 (Volume 482)
    - Cash Book, 1885-1905 (Volume 482a)
  - SAN PEDRO HARBOR DOCK AND LAND COMPANY
    - By laws, 1887 (Volume 483)
    - By laws, 1889
    - Copies of By laws, Minutes, and Business, 1887-1889
    - Stock Journal, 1887-1897
    - Stock Ledger, 1897 (Volume 484)
    - Journal, 1888-1889
    - Ledger, 1888-1889
    - Cash Book, 1888-1897
    - Stock Certificates, 1887-1893 (Volume 485)
  - UNION FUEL COMPANY
    - By laws, 1904 (Volume 486)
    - Amended By laws, 1907 (Volume 487)
    - Minutes, 1906-1910 (Volume 488)
    - Stock Journal, 1904-1906 (Volume 489)
    - Stock Journal and Ledger, 1905 (Volume 490)
    - Stock Ledger, 1904-1906 (Volume 491)
    - Stock Certificates (Volume 492)
    - Stock Certificates (Volume 493)
    - Journal, 1906-1914 (Volume 494)
    - Ledger, 1906-1914 (Volume 495)
    - Coal Data Book, 1907-1908 (Volume 496)
    - Abstracts of Sales, 1908 (Volume 497)
  - MISCELLANEOUS VOLUMES (UNIDENTIFIED)
    - Trial Balance, (S-Z), 1924 (Volume 498)
    - Trial Balance, (A-R), 1926 (Volume 499)
    - Trial Balance, (A-R), 1929-1930 (Volume 500)
    - Trial Balance, (S-Z), 1929-1930 (Volume 501)
    - Ledger, 1878-1880 (Volume 502)
    - Cash Book, 1879-1880 (Volume 503)
    - Cash Book, 1883-1885 (Volume 504)
    - Credit Book, 1930-1931 (Volume 505)
    - Receipts and Disbursements, 1919-1922 (Volume 506)
- Series 5. Maps and Blueprints
  - Subseries 1. San Francisco Property
    - City of San Francisco, showing street railway lines, 1887 (Map-case 1, Othertype 507)
    - San Francisco Water Front (Map-case 1, Othertype 508)
    - San Mateo County-acreage of Charles Crocker, 1885 (Map-case 1, Othertype 509)
    - Street Map of San Francisco, P.I. Co. property (Map-case 1, Othertype 510)
    - Street Map of San Francisco, P.I. Co. property (Map-case 1, Othertype 511)
    - Street Map of portion of San Francisco on the San Francisco Bay (Map-case 1, Othertype 511)
    - Diagram of P.I.Co. Realty in San Francisco, 1901 (Map-case 1, Othertype 512)
      (Sheet 1)
    - P.I.Co. Realty in San Francisco, 1901 (Map-case 1, Othertype 513)
      (Sheet 2)
    - San Francisco Second Street Slip, 1902 (Map-case 1, Othertype 514)
    - Mission Bay, San Francisco (Map-case 1, Othertype 514)
    - San Francisco, San Pablo, and Suisun Bays, 1915 (Map-case 1, Othertype 514)
  - Subseries 2. Berkeley, Oakland, and Alameda Property
    - East Berkeley (Map-case 1, Othertype 515)
    - East Berkeley (Map-case 1, Othertype 516)
    - Oakland Harbor, property of the Oakland Water Front Company, 1903 (Map-case 1, Othertype 517)
    - Oakland Harbor, property of the OWFCo, 1903; Marked with various boundary lines (Map-case 1, Othertype 518)
    - Oakland and Vicinity (Map-case 1, Othertype 519)
    - Oakland and Vicinity (Map-case 1, Othertype 520)
    - Oakland Harbor, 1893 (Map-case 1, Othertype 521)
    - Water Front of City of Oakland, 1893 (Map-case 1, Othertype 522)
    - Oakland Water Front, 1902 (Map-case 2, Othertype 523)
    - Oakland Water Front (Map-case 2, Othertype 524)
    - Alameda Marsh (Map-case 2, Othertype 525)
    - Jones Tract, Alameda County, 1891 (Map-case 2, Othertype 526)
    - Berkeley and Alameda, 1893 (Map-case 2, Othertype 527)
    - Statement of P.I.Co. Realty in Alameda County, 1901 (Map-case 2, Othertype 527)
  - Subseries 3. Monterey Peninsula Property
    - Monterey Peninsula, 1908 (Map-case 2, Othertype 528)
    - Monterey and Fresno Railroad, 1894 (Map-case 2, Othertype 528)
    - P.I.Co. property in vicinity of Monterey (Map-case 2, Othertype 529)
    - P.I.Co. property in vicinity of Monterey (Map-case 2, Othertype 530)
    - Pacific Grove Retreat, 1889 (Map-case 2, Othertype 531)
    - Monterey; Pacific Grove, Hotel Grounds (Map-case 2, Othertype 531)
    - Laurelles Rancho and Adjoining Lands (Map-case 2, Othertype 532)
    - Rancho Los Laurelles (Map-case 2, Othertype 533)
    - Rancho Los Laurelles (Map-case 2, Othertype 534)
    - Rancho Los Laurelles (Map-case 2, Othertype 535)
  - Subseries 4. Castle Crags Property
    - Castle Crags Property, 1894 (Map-case 2, Othertype 536)
  - Subseries 5. Santa Barbara Property
    - San Roqui Creek, Santa Barbara, 1902 (Map-case 3, Othertype 537)
    - Santa Barbara and Vicinity (Map-case 3, Othertype 538)
    - Hope Ranch (Map-case 3, Othertype 539)
    - Hope Ranch and Pipe Line, 1882 (Map-case 3, Othertype 540)
    - Contour Map of Hope Ranch (Map-case 3, Othertype 541)
  - Subseries 6. Louisiana and Texas Property
    - McComb addition to Lafayette, La., 1881 (Map-case 3, Othertype 542)
    - McComb (Map-case 3, Othertype 543)
    - Lafayette, 1891 (Map-case 3, Othertype 544)
    - Lands in and around Lafayette, La., property of Southern Development Company, 1891 (Map-case 3, Othertype 545)
    - Lafayette (Map-case 3, Othertype 546)
    - Southwestern Louisiana (Map-case 3, Othertype 547)
    - Trilby-Acadia Parish, La., 1903 (Map-case 3, Othertype 548)
    - Location of lands belonging to the P.I.Co. in Acadia and St. Landry Parishes, 1897 (Map-case 3, Othertype 549)
    - Official Map, State of Texas, 1882 (Map-case 3, Othertype 550)
    - Map showing Reconnaissance for the extension of the Texas and New Orleans RR, Texas, 1899 (Map-case 4, Othertype 551)
    - City of Lampasas Springs, Lampasas County, Texas, 1899 (Map-case 4, Othertype 552)
    - Llano County, Texas, 1890 (Map-case 4, Othertype 553)
    - Railroad lines in Southeast Texas (Map-case 4, Othertype 554)
    - Sonora (Map-case 4, Othertype 555)
    - Plan showing proposed railways to be constructed under auspices of the Insular Estates (Map-case 4, Othertype 556)
    - Fort Worth (Map-case 4, Othertype 556a)
    - Fort Worth, a portion (Map-case 4, Othertype 556b)
  - Subseries 7. Carbon Hill Coal Company
    - Carbon Hill Coal Co. property, Seattle (Map-case 4, Othertype 557)
    - Pierce County, Washington (Map-case 4, Othertype 558)
    - Carbon Hill Coal Mine (Map-case 4, Othertype 559)
    - Carbon Hill Coal Company's property, Pierce County, 1907 (Map-case 4, Othertype 560)
    - Carbon Hill Coal Co. property (Map-case 4, Othertype 561)
    - Carbon Hill Coal Co. property, Pierce County, 1902 (Map-case 4, Othertype 562)
    - Fairfax Extension, Pierce County (Map-case 4, Othertype 562)
  - Subseries 8. Guatemala Central Railroad
    - Railroad map of Guatemala (Map-case 4, Othertype 563)
    - Guatemala Extension (Map-case 4, Othertype 564)
    - Plans of Ocasitos River Extension Crossing, Ayutla Extension, Guatemala Central RR, 1910 (10 sheets) (Map-case 4, Othertype 564a)
  - Subseries 9. Miscellaneous
    - Capay Valley Land Co. property (Map-case 4, Othertype 565)
    - Profile, Palo Gordo to San Antonio Suchite-pequez (Map-case 5, Othertype 566)
    - Tide Lands Around Sheep Island and Vicinity (Map-case 5, Othertype 567)
    - P.I.Co. land in Tehama County, Calif. (Map-case 5, Othertype 568)
    - Map of Part of Mariposa County, Calif. (Map-case 5, Othertype 569)
    - Visitacion (Map-case 5, Othertype 570)
    - San Bernardino and Redlands Railroad, 1901 (Map-case 5, Othertype 571)
    - Calvert Coal and Clay Co. (Map-case 5, Othertype 572)
    - San Marino, Calif. (Map-case 5, Othertype 573)
    - Map showing overlap of land grants to Atlantic and Pacific Railroad Co. and Southern Pacific Railroad, 1892 (Map-case 5, Othertype 574)
    - Map showing the property of the Pacific Rolling Mill Co., 1882 (Map-case 5, Othertype 575)
    - Paul Tract (Map-case 5, Othertype 576)
    - Map of Croton Point, the property of W.A. Underhill Brick Co., 1903 (Map-case 5, Othertype 577)
    - Plans of factory for installation of Fish Drier (Map-case 5, Othertype 577a)
  - Subseries 10. Santa Clara Coal
    - Santa Clara Coal Concession (Map-case 5, Othertype 578)
    - Plans of working and details of coal seams (Map-case 5, Othertype 579)
    - Santa Clara Coal Fields (Out-crops of coal beds and location of openings) (Map-case 5, Othertype 580)
    - Inventories, 1916-1918 (Map-case 5, Othertype 581)
      Del Monte, Hope Ranch, etc.